A Finding Aid to the Thomas S. Holman Research Materials on Reginald Marsh, 1970-1989, in the Archives of American Art AAA.holmthom
Archives of American Art
Thomas S. Holman research materials on Reginald Marsh
1970-1989
AAA.holmthom
Archives of American Art
1.8 Linear feet
Curator, and gallery director Thomas S. Holman's research materials on Reginald Marsh, 1970-1989, measure 1.8 linear feet. Research materials consist of correspondence, notes, printed material, writings, and images accrued during the course of exhibition research that Holman pursued while he was curator of collections at the Minnesota Museum of American Art and director of the Bell Gallery, Brown University. Reginald Marsh research, mainly conducted from 1982-1983, comprises the vast majority of the collection. In addition, there are research files for proposed Charles Demuth and Charles Sheeler exhibitions. Grant research compiled in 1989 concerns a mural exhibition.
Holman, Thomas S.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Donated by Thomas S. Holman in 2013.
Conditions Governing Access note
Use of original material requires an appointment.
Biographical/Historical note
Art historian Thomas S. Holman has been a curator at the Norton Museum of Art and Minnesota Museum of American Art, and served as executive director of The Hudson River Museum and Marietta/Cobb Museum. He is now an art advisor and lives in New York City.
Reginald Marsh (1898-1954) was best known for his paintings of life in New York City during the Great Depression. Subjects included crowds on city streets and at Coney Island, women, hobos on the Bowery, vaudeville and other popular entertainments.
Arrangement note
The collection is arranged as 1 series:
Series 1: Research Files, 1970-1989 (Boxes 1-3; 1.8 linear feet)
Scope and Contents note
Curator, and gallery director Thomas S. Holman's research materials on Reginald Marsh, 1970-1989, measure 1.8 linear feet. Research materials consist of correspondence, notes, printed material, writings, and images accrued during the course of exhibition research that Holman pursued while he was curator of collections at the Minnesota Museum of American Art and director of the Bell Gallery, Brown University. Reginald Marsh research, mainly conducted from 1982-1983, comprises the vast majority of the collection. In addition, there are research files for proposed Charles Demuth and Charles Sheeler exhibitions. Grant research compiled in 1989 concerns a mural exhibition.
David Winton Bell Gallery (Brown University).; Demuth, Charles, 1883-1935; Marsh, Reginald, 1898-1954; Minnesota Museum of American Art.; Sheeler, Charles, 1883-1965; Arts administrators--New York (State)--New York; Curators--New York (State)--New York; Gallery directors--New York (State)--New York; Mural painting and decoration
- Research Files, 1970-1989; Series 1; 1.8 Linear feet Boxes 1-3
  Scope and Contents note
  This series is comprised of research files concerning a proposed Reginald Marsh exhibition for the Minnesota Museum of American Art. Correspondence indicates the show was planned for fall 1982 and rescheduled for spring 1983. Later letters mention an anticipated date of winter 1985-86. Holman left the Minnesota Museum of American Art 1984, and there is no evidence that a Reginald Marsh exhibition was ever held there. A substantial amount of correspondence is with William Benton, numerous Benton family members, and The William Benton Museum of Art at The University of Connecticut, Storrs. Other correspondents include institutional and private owners of works by Marsh, and artists who knew Marsh. Research files also include printed material, notes, writings, and photographs.
  In addition, single research files concern Charles Demuth and Charles Sheeler exhibitions planned for the Minnesota Museum of American Art. Another file contains grant research for a mural exhibition conducted in 1989 when Holman was Director of the Bell Gallery, Brown University.
  The bulk of the material is dated 1982-1983. The majority of records dated prior to 1981 or 1984-1988 are original printed material; dates in parentheses indicate publication dates of photocopied items.
  Arrangement note
  Files are arranged alphabetically by subject of research.
  - Demuth, Charles - Exhibition Research (1959-1979), 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
  - Marsh, Reginald - Exhibition Research (Box 1)
    - Akron Art Museum, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Albion College, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 4, Folder 7)
    - American Academy and Institute of Arts and Letters, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Amherst College, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Archer M. Huntington Art Gallery, The University of Texas at Austin, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Arizona State University, Tempe, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Art Gallery of Hamilton [Ontario], 1982 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - The Art Institute of Chicago, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Artists, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Ball State University Art Gallery, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - The Baltimore Museum of Art, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Benton, Charles, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Benton Family (1974), circa 1982 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Benton, John, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Benton, William (1940-1976), 1982 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - The Berkshire Museum, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Blount Collection, circa 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - The Boise Gallery of Art, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Boley, Helen Benton, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - The Boston Athenaeum, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Boston Public Library, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Bowdoin College Museum of Art, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Brigham Young University, Art Gallery, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Brodman, Mr. and Mrs. Keeve, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - The Brooklyn Museum, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Brooks Memorial Art Gallery, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Burpee Art Museum/Rockford Art Association, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - The Butler Institute of American Art, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - The Canton Art Institute, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Carnegie Institute, Museum of Art, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Catalogs, Brochures, etc., (1969-1982), undated; 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Charles H. MacNider Museum, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - The Chrysler Museum, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Cincinnati Art Museum, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - The Cleveland Museum of Art, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Colby College Museum of Art, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Colorado Springs Fine Arts Center, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Columbus Museum of Art, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - The Corcoran Gallery of Art (1972), 1982 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Cranbrook Acadmey/Museum, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Dallas Museum of Fine Arts, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Davenport Art Gallery, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - The Dayton Art Institute, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Delaware Art Museum, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Des Moines Art Center (1967), 1982 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - The Detroit Institute of Arts, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Doss, Erika (1939-1982) (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Edwin A. Ulrich Museum of Art, Wichita State University, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - The Everson Museum of Art (1969), 1980-1982 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - The Fine Arts Museum of the South at Mobile, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Flint Institute of Arts, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Fogg Art Museum, Harvard University, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - The Fort Worth Art Museum, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - Galleries, 1981-1983 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - Galleries of the Claremont Colleges (1980), 1982 (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - Georgia Museum of Art, The University of Georgia, Athens, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - Gibbes Art Gallery, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - The Godwin-Ternbach Museum, Queens College, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 60)
    - Goodrich, Lloyd (undated, 1980), 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 61)
    - Harnett, Leila, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 62)
    - Hay, John (1944), 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 63)
    - Helen Foresman Spencer Museum of Art, The University of Kansas, Lawrence, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 64)
    - Herbert F. Johnson Museum of Art, Cornell University, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 65)
    - Hirschl & Adler Galleries, Inc., 1983 (Box 1, Folder 66)
    - The High Museum of Art, 1982 (Binder 1, Flat-file 67, Box 1, Folder 67)
    - Hills, Patricia, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 68)
    - Hirshhorn Museum and Sculpture Garden (1949), 1982 (Box 1, Folder 69)
    - Hopkins, Minnesota, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 70)
    - Housatonic Community College, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 71)
    - Hunter Museum of Art, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 72)
    - Huntington Galleries, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 73)
    - Huntsville Museum of Art, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 74)
    - IBM Art Collection, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 75)
    - Interested in Exhibition, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 76)
    - The Jane Voorhees Zimmerli Art Museum, Rutgers University (circa 1980-circa 1982) (Box 1, Folder 77)
    - The John and Mabel Ringling Museum of Art (1931), 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 78)
    - Joslyn Art Museum, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 79)
    - Kalamazoo Institute of Art (1973), 1982 (Box 1, Folder 80)
    - Kelley, Augustus M., 1983 (Box 1, Folder 81)
    - Krannert Art Museum, University of Illinois, Urbana-Champaign, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 82)
    - Kresge Art Center Gallery, Michigan State University, East Lansing, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 83)
    - Lafayette Art Center, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 84)
    - La Jolla Museum of Contemporary Art, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 85)
    - Laning, Edward (1952), circa 1982-circa 1983 (Box 1, Folder 86)
    - Lauren Rogers Library and Museum of Art, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 87)
    - Lehigh University Art Galleries, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 88)
    - Lists of Works, circa 1982-circa 1983 (Box 1, Folder 89)
    - Los Angeles County Museum of Art, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 90)
    - The Lowe Art Museum, The University of Miami, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 91)
    - Lumet, Sidney, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 92)
    - Lyman Allyn Museum, 1982; 1983 (Box 1, Folder 93)
    - Madison Art Center, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 94)
    - The Maryland Institute, College of Art (1978-1980), 1982 (Box 1, Folder 95)
    - Mass Mailing, circa 1982 (Box 1, Folder 96)
    - Meadows Museum of Art, Centenary College of Louisiana, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 97)
    - Memorial Art Gallery, University of Rochester, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 98)
    - The Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 99)
    - The Minneapolis Institute of Arts, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 100)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence (1950-1964), 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 101)
    - Miscellaneous Images, 1982-circa 1983 (Box 1, Folder 102)
    - Miscellaneous Notes, circa 1982-circa 1983 (Box 1, Folder 103)
    - Miscellaneous Notes, Bibliographic, circa 1982-circa 1983 (Box 1, Folder 104)
    - Miscellaneous Printed Material (1923-1979), circa 1982-circa 1983 (Box 1, Folder 105)
    - The Montclair Art Museum (1977), 1982 (Box 1, Folder 106)
    - Montgomery Museum of Fine Arts (1979), 1982 (Box 1, Folder 107)
    - Moravian College (1954), 1983 (Box 1, Folder 108)
    - Munson-Williams-Proctor Institute, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 109)
    - Museum of Art of Ogunquit, 1970-1982 (Box 1, Folder 110)
    - Museum of Fine Arts, Boston, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 111)
    - Museum of Fine Arts, Houston, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 112)
    - Museum of Fine Arts, Springfield, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 113)
    - Museum of the City of New York, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 114)
    - Muskegon Museum of Art, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 115)
    - National Academy of Design (1979), 1982 (Box 1, Folder 116, Folder 115)
    - National Gallery of Art, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 117)
    - National Museum of American Art, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 118)
    - Negative Replies [not owners of Marsh's work], 1982 (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
    - New Orleans Museum of Art, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - The New-York Historical Society, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - The New Yorker, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Newport Harbor Art Museum, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Norton Simon Museum of Art at Pasadena, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Oklahoma Art Center, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Owensboro Museum of Fine Art, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Palm Beach Institute of Art (1960-1982), circa 1982-circa 1983 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - The Parrish Art Museum, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - The Peale Museum, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Pennsylvania Academy of the Fine Arts (1956), 1982 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Philadelphia Museum of Art (1980), 1982 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Philbrook Art Center, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - The Phillips Collection, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Phoenix Art Museum, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - The Pierpont Morgan Library, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Portland [Oregon] Art Museum, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Portland [Maine] Museum of Art, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Princeton University, The Art Museum, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Private Collections, Miscellaneous, 1982-1984 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute (undated, 1959), 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Rhode Island School of Design, Museum of Art, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Roanoke Museum of Fine Arts, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Robert Hull Fleming Museum, The University of Vermont (1977-1978), 1982 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Rose Art Museum, Brandeis University, 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - The St. Louis Art Museum, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Sammlung Thyssen-Bornemisza (1943), circa 1982-circa 1983 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - San Diego Museum of Art, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - The Santa Barbara Museum of Art, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Sasowsky, Norman, 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Seattle Art Museum, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Sheldon Memorial Art Gallery, University of Nebraska Lincoln, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - The Sheldon Swope Art Gallery, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Sid Deutsch Galleries, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Sioux City Art Center, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - The Sketchbooks of Reginald Marsh (1972), 1982 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Smith College Museum of Art, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - The Snite Museum of Art, University of Notre Dame, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Sotheby's (1954-1982), 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - State University of New York at Binghamton, University Art Gallery, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - State University of New York at Oswego, Tyler Art Gallery, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Syracuse University, University Art Collections (1939), 1982 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - The Telfair Academy of Arts and Sciences, Inc., 1982 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Terra Museum of American Art, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - The Toledo Museum of Art, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Tomoka State Park, 1983-1984 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Tweed Museum of Art, University of Minnesota, Duluth, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - University of Arizona, Tucson, Museum of Art, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - University of California, Berkeley, University Art Museum, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - The University of Iowa, Iowa City, Museum of Art, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - University of Maryland, College Park, The Art Gallery, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - The University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, Museum of Art, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 14, Flat-file 14)
    - University of Minnesota, Twin Cities, University Gallery, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - The University of New Mexico, Albuquerque, The Art Museum, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - University of Oregon, Eugene, Museum of Art, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - The University of Virginia, Charlottesville, Art Museum, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - University of Wyoming, Laramie, Art Museum, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Valente, Mrs. Alfredo and Richard G. Valente, 1983-1984 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Vassar College Art Gallery, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Virginia Museum of Fine Arts, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Wadsworth Atheneum, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Wagner, Louise Benton, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Walker Art Center, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Weatherspoon Art Gallery, The University of North Carolina at Greensboro, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - West Point Museum, Department of the Army, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Whitney Museum of American Art (1930-1936), 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - William A. Farnsworth Library and Art Museum, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - The William Benton Museum of Art, The University of Connecticut, Storrs, 1973-1983 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - William Rockhill Nelson Gallery of Art, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Williams College Museum of Art, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - The Wood Art Gallery, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Woodhouse, Betty Burroughs, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - The Woodstock Historical Society, Inc. (1954), 1983 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Worcester Art Museum, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Yale University Art Gallery, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Mural Exhibition Grant Research (1932-1983), 1989 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Sheeler, Charles - Exhibition Research, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 39)